pbskidsplay.org 2014-07-19

# PBS KIDS PLAY! School readiness program - Educational games - Preschool games - Adaptive learning games

_Last modified on June 14, 2011. ****_

This Privacy Policy explains how PBS collects, uses, and protects your personal information in relation to PBS KIDS PLAY!SM. Please note that by using PBS KIDS PLAY!, you are agreeing to the terms of this privacy policy, which differs from the privacy policies of other PBS websites. Here is the bottom line: PBS WILL NOT, UNDER ANY CIRCUMSTANCES, SELL OR RENT YOUR PERSONAL INFORMATION TO ANY THIRD PARTY. 

Following is a description of the personal information PBS may collect from you and how we use that information:

### Your email address.

PBS has a zero-spam policy. This means that, except in the specific circumstances noted below, **we do not send you any emails unless you expressly opt into our mailing list**. We will always honor your request to remove you from the list in a timely manner.

**The following are circumstances under which we may send emails to you, _without your prior explicit permission_** (i.e., even if you do not opt in):

  1. We will send you one confirmation email when you have created a trial account.
  2. We will send you up to two reminder emails when your trial or subscription is about to expire.
  3. We will send you one confirmation email when you have subscribed to, modified, or canceled a subscription to PBS KIDS PLAY!
  4. We may alert you if there is an issue with your subscription account or any other circumstance that could result in a disruption of service or breach of security.

### Your friend's email address.

You can easily refer friends to PBS KIDS PLAY! with our "Tell a Friend" feature. If you choose to use this feature, PBS will send one personalized email to your friend about PBS KIDS PLAY!. We will not, under any circumstances, sell or rent your friend's email address and we will not send any further emails to his or her address without his or her explicit request to do so.

### Your phone number.

We may ask for your (or your organization's) phone number either during trial registration (Classroom Edition only) or if you make a purchase. The following are circumstances under which we may call you, without your prior explicit permission:

  1. We may alert you if there is an issue with your subscription account or any other circumstance that could result in a disruption of service or breach of security.
  2. We may call you in an attempt to respond to your inquiry in the event you provide an email address that bounces back to us.
  3. For Classroom Edition trial accounts ONLY, we may call your organization as a follow-up to your classroom trial.

### Your child's username.

A "username" is a nickname that you create for each child who uses PBS KIDS PLAY! This username can be fictional and does not include the child's family name. (Using a fictional username can help protect your child's identity.) It is used solely for the purpose of personalizing PBS KIDS PLAY! for your child and personalizing the learning progress reports for you. PBS will not, under any circumstances, use the username for the purpose of advertising products to you or your child.

### Your child's birthday.

This information is not required by PBS in order to provide service, but is designed solely to enhance your child’s experience. This information will not be sold or rented and will not be used to advertise products to you or your child.

### Your child's learning profile.

Because we track each child's learning progress for you, we collect data on each child's usage of various games and videos in PBS KIDS PLAY!. We only access this usage data in an aggregate, anonymous way and keep such data in a separate database from your account information. This data allows PBS to provide your child with the appropriate level of challenge in learning games and also helps us to evaluate the efficacy of our interactive curriculum. PBS' policy is to retain profile data for as long as feasible (generally 6 months or longer) in order to enable subscribers who cancel to easily renew a lapsed subscription. If you wish PBS to permanently erase this data, please email support@pbskidsplay.org.

### Your billing information.

(This applies only to paying subscribers.) When you subscribe to PBS KIDS PLAY!, we collect your full name, billing address and payment method. We do not send you any mailings unless you expressly opt into our mailing list. If you do opt in, you may receive mailings from your local PBS station, such as a local program guide or public television membership offer. PBS does not store or have access to your credit card number (excepting the last four digits) or your three-digit security code. The payment method is shared only with your financial institution.

### Optional survey information.

We may ask you to tell us additional information about your experience with PBS KIDS PLAY! in order to better understand audience preferences and how you would like to see the service improved. This information will be kept strictly confidential. PBS will not quote you for a product testimonial or use your name without your express permission.

### CHILDREN UNDER THE AGE OF 18

PBS requires that a parent or legal guardian register for PBS KIDS PLAY! and manage the account. PBS KIDS PLAY! is not intended to collect personally identifying information from any person aged 18 and under **.** PBS will not, under any circumstances, ask your child to enter any personal information on PBS KIDS PLAY!.

### NO Advertising

PBS KIDS PLAY! contains no advertising or product placement.

### Cookies

A cookie is information that PBS KIDS PLAY! may put on your computer's hard drive so that PBS can (1) identify the terms of any special offers you may have obtained, such as price discount or free trial period AND/OR (2) automatically sign you in so that you do not have to enter a username and password each time you visit. No personal information is ever stored in a PBS KIDS PLAY! cookie, even if you have entered personal information in other parts of PBS KIDS PLAY!. 

### Sharing of Information

PBS will not, under any circumstances sell or rent your information to any party. PBS may engage other companies to provide services on its behalf, including but not limited to hosting, billing, marketing, and customer support for the PBS KIDS PLAY! service. We only provide these companies the minimum information reasonably required to perform the service, and they are prohibited from using that information for any other purpose. All companies who perform services for PBS KIDS PLAY! comply with the Payment Card Industry (PCI) Data Security Standard.

PBS may disclose your personally identifying information if required to do so by law or in the good-faith belief that such action is necessary to: (a) conform to legal requirements or comply with a legal governmental request; (b) protect and defend the rights or property of PBS or its licensors; (c) enforce the Terms and Conditions; or (d) act in urgent circumstances to protect data security.

### Modifications to the Privacy Policy

This policy is subject to change from time to time, and your continued use of PBS KIDS PLAY! is conditioned upon your acceptance of any modifications hereto.

If you have any questions or concerns regarding this policy, please email [feedback@pbskidsplay.org](mailto:feedback@pbskidsplay.org). You may also mail us at the Public Broadcasting Service, 2100 Crystal Drive, Arlington, VA 22202, ATTN: PBS KIDS PLAY.
